how are you today is the 8th of
april 2012.
what we've got are just a couple of ring
magnets
which are circular type magnets
and these are set up north south north
south
and they attract pretty heavily
or they don't
you can see they they push away or twist
i don't want to go to this particular
washer
so i go to the ends
like that and on the magnet they can
hear
the the clink of the attraction
so there's that's it's repelling on
those
this is a stainless steel washer
in that middle area that one
and just doesn't want to go to this
other one it really doesn't want to go
to it as well but
you can get it to go to it if you put it
at 90 degrees
so what i want to do is i just want to
show you
the action of repelling
so you can you can see
that the the magnets repel and
they don't go together they just they
fire
up so can you see that happening or do
we need to color this one
pretty rough so what i just want to do
is i just want to
separate this particular one
one more time
let's get a slide in the past very
gently
and just to show you some
different reactions that can take place
so this is in
repulsion okay so this is where the
fields don't go together
and as you can see we've made a mistake
with this particular one
where it does go together so this is
quite unusual
and with a slight amount of movement
it's again
i don't know if you saw that or not
retraction
and repulsion so just one more time
so that it's holding all right
just so that you can see that
whilst it was an attraction it
it now has the ability to just
i'll just get back a little bit further
to the camera just so you can see this
i'm just going to float the washer
near it and it'll pull it away
nah you can't do that that's cheating
to show that it can be done twice in a
row
maybe
just got to balance this
in its right location
also so you can
see it you might want to just go back a
fraction more
so that you can see it in action
that's approximately four feet jumping
okay um
so what else can you use it for
apart from jumping maintenance
there um
because because normally they don't do
this at all
so we've got this mechanism
possibly
you didn't even catch it okay yeah
that's like that so what else can it be
used for well we're using it for
uh aligning water
we're using the attraction
that is normally repulsed
for water to
spin around
a magnetic field
and i just want to show
that we can drop the
magnet from a grade height a slight
angle
on a slight angle it will repulse
okay so just to prove again it's rip off
now if we bring it to perpendicular
it should attract all right
one more time make sure that we're
straight
how bad did it so predicting its
behavior is some of the things that we
want
to be able to do with magnetic field
you'll notice that
large washer there holds out at 45
degrees before it actually resolves
and just to prove it i'll move it to the
top
put it in the perpendicular horizontal
that's horizontal isn't it to the
ah you know what i mean it's directly
upright how's that
so it's 90 degrees to horizontal
there
all right well we're predicting that
well it'll repel normally
okay
something's going on who's played with
it
ah they just must belong to goldilocks
oh the three bears
okay it's going to make a lower of me
which is good
thank you it will happen
with persistence all right
so we're looking at
why and what happens with this
particular action
so folding that up allows it to release
and come away so that's just one of the
other actions of it
um showing
that it actually has more power
it's a bit hard oh well not really
i'll show this
in in attraction
is very very strong
here it doesn't attract turd at all
but here it's experiment
i just want to couldn't
couldn't see my hands were in the way
weren't they
now i showed you where there's twins
they don't go together
and doesn't matter what you do they just
won't come together at all
but if we bring a cousin in
it might
it might go together
i'd like to just put a little bit of
slippery on
just so that they'll bind maybe
come on
gonna make alarms
a bigger one yeah bigger one or better
but
i want to just get this one in
anyway it attracts and repels with the
ones
at the one time
good for morse code
it's not that hard just doesn't want to
stick
okay so get rid of that one
or bring the other one into play
so this is now four washers
like we had before
full attraction but a lot of
a lot of extra power associated
with these
very hard to form apart normally
all right so has that driven your
nutshell you can
everybody can do that now put your hands
up
now you put your hand down
so just remember you can't do this and
you'll be right
right if you're told something just
remember it's not true
until you've done it and proven it to
yourself that it's not true
so um why
does it normally repulse
and yet here it's attracting okay so
these magnetic fields
we know for sure that they repulse
because that's what it's doing
has that silly been occupied
there are just beautiful and
to see them come into attraction at that
point
is just phenomenal okay
the field i've just put my thumb on just
so that
you can hear or just see
the intensity that's gotta come in
to remove that field
so it's not that i'm super strong or
anything
making it go that way but
it's pretty exciting guys
only because it can't be done so you
can't do that remember
they they repel right as they should
so it shouldn't stay there it shouldn't
be doing what
that's doing at the moment so i don't
know what we've done
i don't think any any of you out there
know what we've done but
if you do happen to know what we've done
and you like what we've done
please send money because that's the
only reason we can keep
playing is that we uh we need to exist
so you know like i don't drive a
rolls-royce yet but
listen you know daimler's or um you know
things like
rolls royces um mercedes benz
whatever you know we'll stuff them up
we'll play with them and
have a bit of fun driving them around
the countryside
um make sure they come with plenty of
fuel first place
and or a fuel car you know
we just love showing you this stuff
because we know it'll drive you know
okay so there you go
that's about this magnet let me just
show you some of the other stuff we're
doing
you'll notice some of our little
experiments are there
and these are pretty unique
we're using these to disrupt
water so they fire down
through their water flows in this end
and comes out the sand and because it
does that
it actually magnetizes the water and
brings the water back to individual
particles
or if you like the term as i like the
term
we could refer to being polly water
my father once told me what polly water
was
uh in when i inquired and he
uh directly told me of course that it
was paris
so that's the term polly water
has always remained a favorite of mine
from polly
polly the parrot i'll probably put the
kettle on um
so this way with how we're using polly's
kettle
so this is absolutely intriguing
and what it does so you can follow these
up
we're going to be doing some experiments
shortly where this will be all videos
and with water and everything flowing
through it you'll be able to see it
in total action but this is just the
initial experiment
of why we're doing it the way we're
doing it so we've got them
with uh with threes and fours
um four of them work really well
um threes i've been told don't work
so that's why we're going to do it with
three and
we'll get the best response out of three
because they don't work
we've got balls
and i hope you do too but anyway that's
what it's all about
get yourself some magnets play with them
if you've got a heart that's dropped one
of those
pacemakers attached to it don't play
with it
leave it alone leave your heart alone
give it
remember to donate all the bits you're
not using if you're dead
you know somebody else might be able to
use it
we could play with them
we could use a thigh bone down here or
something you know something that's a
little bit different
we just like to see what things do and
why they do what they do
so this is how you begin to play you
just use different magnetic structures
and
different types of magnets
these are called rattlesnake eggs
they're only allowed as
kids toys just remember your kids are a
lot smarter than you
it's just that if they happen to be
playing with these
uh they actually have a ball with them
we wind them the magnets up
and they unwind um which is quite
quite a unique thing to see if i can do
it
do it properly it will spin back
hitting my thumb i had to fix that
add one
so as they go around
i'll go back to the facing more where is
north on these
they don't know because you can move
them back to there and they'll stay
there
so what we found is that
when you push the magnet together
they'll touch on the end but if you turn
it at 90 degrees they'll repel
so just by a simple twist they don't go
together
so that's the field the field is in the
middle
sits right in the middle
so pretty spectacular stuff
where you can wind the power of the
magnet up
it actually makes them stronger to pull
apart
and that's weird how many of you know
that you can actually
wind a magnetic field
so play with them see what you can do
and um if you haven't got the time to
play with them send me the money so that
we can play with them
and uh we just do this
because we just love driving the nuts
and showing what you're missing out on
yeah so that's it good enough
taking my time buzz off and send money
thank you that'll do